Hello friends, welcome to the Indian Money YouTube channel.
My name is Siddharth Narayan.
We have some questions related to
home insurance. Some people
want to know what it is, should we take it
or not, how it works, etc.
So let's discuss a little about it. What is it, what
things do we have to keep in
mind, it has to be mixed,
that also has to be seen. There are many
mixes with which people take it. Yes, if they
take this, then some other powder is necessary,
they take that. So let's quickly discuss
about it.
One is that home insurance penetration in our country is
very low. People don't know everything about it,
and if they do know, they do
n't feel the need for something like this. It is
very important. It is someone's house, your
own house, this is a dilapidated apartment, flat, or
anything else. Just imagine, if tomorrow there is a
natural calamity, something happens, some
accident occurs, so like houses get
damaged, what will happen if you don't have an insurance policy in such a situation?
All these things come to mind in the country only
when something is available.  It has already happened and then the thought
comes out and it is so good, so it is a
good thing to take home insurance
and it is not very expensive or has a very high premium, it is
not good either
and we can support you
and secondly, home insurance is of
two types, one covers the house and
secondly, it can cover the goods inside the house, that is,
you understand the house, goods like
electronic items, kitchen items,
appliances, furniture, there are many
such goods, if you want to go to the
market or if something gets stolen, then
what will you do, then this stone will be useful, there are
normal soil type missions,
one is Bay Fire and Left Foot, in
which if a fire breaks out in Muzaffarnagar, something like this happens, then
you can take it in that session at this
time
and secondly, there is Burglary and Burglary, that is,
theft in the house, house break-in,
your goods are taken away, that type of thing
and thirdly, there is Householders Package, that is, it covers
all the things and covers the goods inside the house like the house, so it
covers the goods inside the house  It
is also covering damage caused by fire or theft,
that too is covered,
all things are covered. Now let's talk about
some special things for which they
think that we need it, how should we do it,
if we buy from here then there is
no need for anything else, so that is
23 times more, like people
think that if I buy from this then
I don't need any other insurance, this also
means there is no logic in this, this is
for home, it is not for the people living inside the home,
life insurance is a different thing, it is a different
thing from this
and the second thing is that home insurance is only
required for the owner of the house,
if a tenant lives there, well he does
not need to take it, this is a wrong notion, if there is a house
owner and you live as a tenant, then the
owner of the house will only take the responsibility of the house,
if a tenant's belongings are inside the house then the
landlord is responsible for it, not if the landlord is on rent, it is a
different
thing, but he owns the house but the
belongings inside it are for the tenant.  If
he himself has to arrange for other belongings, then the
responsibility of their insurance lies with the
tenant, he should take
full rights, he is
not the owner of that house, the belongings inside that house are
his, so he should take insurance for that and he
can take it, thirdly,
people think that if I have taken care of it then there is nothing like that,
you will have to check every policy, you will have to
talk to your doctor, there are
many loopholes which also provide this kind of recovery,
so do not think at all whether natural
calamities are covered or not, first see
what is written in the policy,
talk to your agent or advisor accordingly, he has the correct
information,
so this was a small moment on Home
Minister, I hope you liked it,
all these topics were
covered except steps, not only
this, it is on personal finance,
do business, we cover many topics, I would
request you to download our app,
watch its videos,
subscribe, it is written on the screen, if you
use my Mehra then you will get
₹ 2000  You can also get a discount of up to Rs.
If you liked my video then
please like and share it and I will
meet you again very soon. Thank you very much.